<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Mr. Senko - Open Source Wizards</title><link href="http://mrsenko.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://mrsenko.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://mrsenko.com/</id><updated>2016-02-03T22:30:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>January 2016 Report</title><link href="http://mrsenko.com/blog/2016/02/03/january-2016-report/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-03T22:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Todorov</name></author><id>tag:mrsenko.com,2016-02-03:blog/2016/02/03/january-2016-report/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is my first status report for &lt;a href="http://MrSenko.com"&gt;Mr. Senko&lt;/a&gt;. During
January 2016 I've worked on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improvements to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/gilsondev/pelican-clean-blog/pulls?q=is%3Apr+author%3Aatodorov+is%3Aclosed"&gt;pelican-clean-blog&lt;/a&gt;
theme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;URL updates in &lt;code&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; for several Node.js packages;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.spec file to build RPMs for
&lt;a href="https://github.com/django-ses/django-ses/pull/83"&gt;django-ses&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New test case for
&lt;a href="https://github.com/belgian-elixir-study-group/efl/pull/5"&gt;Elixir study exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates to an old PR for
&lt;a href="https://github.com/sphinx-doc/sphinx/pull/1902"&gt;Sphinx&lt;/a&gt; which also fixes a
new regression;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filed a
&lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican/issues/1902"&gt;RFE&lt;/a&gt; against Pelican
and will continue working on it this month.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sphinx broke&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sphinx changes are particularly interesting - the fix for
issue #656 in commit 4c4450d changes the Graphviz's
&lt;code&gt;node['options']&lt;/code&gt; type from &lt;code&gt;list&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;dict&lt;/code&gt; which in turn breaks
&lt;code&gt;html_visit_inheritance_diagram()&lt;/code&gt; and the inheritance_diagram extension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My previous work on this PR introduced some basic tests, which were missing
and they caught the type change! Because the tests and my latest changes are
not yet merged into master the &lt;code&gt;inheritance_diagram.py&lt;/code&gt; extension is still
broken! The tests fail in Travis-CI but probably due to &lt;code&gt;dot&lt;/code&gt; not being
installed. Locally everything seems to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its also worth mentioning that it's been 2 weeks since I've updated my PR
and a bit more since Sphinx introduced the regression. As far as I can see
there's not been any updates with respect to this. 
If you'd like to get a
faster response cycle please &lt;strong&gt;consider subscribing to
&lt;a href="/subscribe.html"&gt;Mr. Senko&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Python"></category></entry><entry><title>FOSDEM 2016 Report</title><link href="http://mrsenko.com/blog/2016/01/31/fosdem-2016-report/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-31T19:30:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Mr. Senko</name></author><id>tag:mrsenko.com,2016-01-31:blog/2016/01/31/fosdem-2016-report/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, &lt;a href="http://MrSenko.com"&gt;Mr. Senko&lt;/a&gt; flew to Brussels for his first
public appearances and we are very excited about this. He visited
&lt;a href="http://fosdem.org"&gt;FOSDEM&lt;/a&gt; to get an update on the latest news in open source
and scored the highest ping-pong score for
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/atodorov_/status/693762736765976576"&gt;BBC Open Source&lt;/a&gt;
on Sunday!
He also learned a bit about &lt;a href="http://elixir-lang.org"&gt;Elixir&lt;/a&gt; with the
Belgian Elixir Study group, attended a panel on open source and start-ups
organized by &lt;a href="http://europe.startupbus.com"&gt;The Startup Bus&lt;/a&gt;
and made lots of new friends. Here are some of
the details and links for further reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Ping-pong with computers" src="/images/bbc_ping_pong.jpg" title="Ping-pong with computers" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Friday - Day 0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday was a fruitful day for Mr. Senko. It started with a meeting at
&lt;a href="http://betacowork"&gt;BetaCowork&lt;/a&gt; - one of the co-working spaces in Brussels
and continued with a visit to
&lt;a href="http://www.erlang-factory.com/brussels2016/"&gt;Brussels Erlang Factory Lite&lt;/a&gt;
where we learned a bit about Erlang and Elixir and even managed to create a
&lt;a href="https://github.com/belgian-elixir-study-group/efl/pull/5"&gt;small pull request&lt;/a&gt;
as part of the exercises. Funny enough, one of the organizers,
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/less_software"&gt;Yuri Leikind&lt;/a&gt; was spot on to recognize our
Bulgarian accent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BetaCowork was bursting with people who've come for FOSDEM. There was a GNOME
team and the Libre Office Italian team! The place is huge and is definitely
an alternative for the entrepreneurs who are tired of working from home! It
is also very close to ULB so next time you visit FOSDEM definitely check their
events schedule as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Saturday - Day 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saturday was the
&lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/track/testing_and_automation/"&gt;Testing and Automation&lt;/a&gt;
day. The morning track showed us &lt;a href="http://frida.re"&gt;Frida&lt;/a&gt; - a tool
which injects JavaScript into existing processes and could be used for testing
interoperability with closed source applications. Another interesting use case
is overriding the standard &lt;code&gt;read&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;write&lt;/code&gt; functions in order to automate testing
of interactive text based applications on Linux. Mr. Senko had the pleasure talking
to Frida's authors on both days. These are extremely tallented and knowledgeable
folks so definitely keep an eye on their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon the room got packed when Marcin and Lukasz presented their
experience with
&lt;a href="https://github.com/jenkinsci/job-dsl-plugin"&gt;Jenkins Job DSL&lt;/a&gt; plugin.
The plugin is very flexible and powerfull, using Groovy
as its programming language. The only drawback is that it is
sometimes too complex to use and requires a steep learning curve.
Regardless of this the only tools we know about related to
Jenkins as Code are the Jenkins Job DSL and Jenkins Job Builder plugins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the evening Mr. Senko visited a panel talk about
&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/startupbusaccelerate-the-impact-of-open-source-software-on-the-tech-industry-tickets-20869395925"&gt;the impact of open source on the tech industry&lt;/a&gt;
at the second big co-workign space in Brussels - &lt;a href="http://co-station.com"&gt;Co.Station&lt;/a&gt;.
The place is in the city center so definitely worth to visit at any time.
Mr. Senko made quite a few new friends there and possibly found potential
pilot customers. We've also made contact with the organizers of
&lt;a href="http://europe.startupbus.com"&gt;Startup Bus Europe&lt;/a&gt; and hopefully we'll see
the bus coming to Sofia as well. And we also got invited to the first
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/setting-up-first-angular-conference-belgium-sam-vloeberghs"&gt;Angular.js conference in Belgium&lt;/a&gt;
and with a bit of luck you'll see a talk from us in the summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sunday - Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sunday was the lazy day. The only talk of interest to Mr. Senko was
&lt;a href="https://fosdem.org/2016/schedule/event/tweaking_ruby_gc/"&gt;Tweaking Ruby GC parameters for speed and profit&lt;/a&gt;
. The rest of the time was spent networking, collecting t-shirts,
reporting
&lt;a href="https://fedorahosted.org/fedora-infrastructure/ticket/5085"&gt;a bug against Fedora Account System&lt;/a&gt;
and meeting with old friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="hammer down" src="/images/bbc_hammer_game.jpg" title="hammer down" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the early afternoon Mr. Senko played a few geeky games at the BBC Open Source
stand. BBC is developing the &lt;a href="https://www.microbit.co.uk/"&gt;micro:bit&lt;/a&gt; - a small computer which is intended to
teach programming to small children. With its help they has built a ping-pong
device which counts how many times you hit the ball.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the second game you had to smash a
red circle with a foam hammer as soon as it lighted up. Mr. Senko managed to
win the first game and then lost the second one. He even got to test the device
and tried to crash it by scoring penalty points when the counter was still zero.
BBC definitely did their job right because the device didn't crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to read this report. See you at the next event!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Founding of Mr. Senko</title><link href="http://mrsenko.com/blog/2016/01/10/founding-of-mr-senko/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-10T14:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Alexander Todorov</name></author><id>tag:mrsenko.com,2016-01-10:blog/2016/01/10/founding-of-mr-senko/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone, welcome to &lt;a href="http://MrSenko.com"&gt;Mr. Senko&lt;/a&gt;! We are a group of friends who have
been working with open source for the last 10 years. During this time we've
seen technologies come and go and hype projects becoming abandoned months later.
We've seen the pain when companies had to rewrite their software because of this
and the struggle to get your patches accepted upstream.
Don't you wish you had somebody who could take care of all the hassle for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mr. Senko is our attempt at providing commercial support for open source projects,
specifically libraries which other companies use to build their products. As of now
we have diverse experience in Java, Python and JavaScript as well as my personal
experience with Quality Assurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next weeks and months we will be refining our value proposition and building
the team so we can offer you great technical support and expertise. We plan to blog
regularly about our progress and about technology and open source events in general! 
You can follow us at &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/Mr_Senko"&gt;@Mr_Senko&lt;/a&gt; or tweet at the wizard
using the &lt;strong&gt;#MrSenko&lt;/strong&gt; hashtag! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more news!&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>